before you learn about Rings you should
really learn about groups so if you
haven't already watched our group video
then hit the pause button and check it
out all wait go
on roughly speaking a ring is a set of
elements where you can add subtract and
multiply but you may not be able to
divide and multiplication may not be
commutative for example the 2 x two
matrices with real numbers form a ring
and matrix multiplication is not
commutative by not requiring a
multiplication to be commutative Rings
generalize things like matrices which
are pretty important by the way did you
notice I said elements instead of
numbers H that's because some rings
consist of numbers While others are made
of more exotic objects like pols or
matrices before we give a more precise
definition let's see some
examples the integers are a ring you can
add subtract and multiply LLY any two
integers and you'll get another integer
but can you divide two integers H well
yes but you may not get an integer if
you divide 3 by five you get a fraction
not an integer that's key if you add
subtract or multiply two elements in the
ring you get another element in the ring
we say the ring is closed under addition
and multiplication what happens in the
ring stays in the
ring another example of a ring is the
set of polinomial with integer
coefficients you can freely add subtract
and multiply two such polinomial and you
will get a third polinomial of this type
but division no I don't think so if you
divide x +1 by x -1 you get x +1 over x
-1 hey it's a thing but it's not a
polinomial so now for the official
definition a ring is a set of elements
with two operations addition and
multiplication if you add two elements
in a ring you get another element in the
ring but earlier I said you can add and
subtract in a ring what gives well
subtraction is just the same as adding
inverses so when I said you can add and
subtract I was essentially saying that
rings have negative elements and if you
add an element to its negative you get
zero so in a ring the elements are a
group under addition better yet addition
is commutative in
rings now here's where things get
serious if you multiply two elements in
a ring you get another element in the
ring it's close under multiplication no
surprise there but elements may not have
inverses under multiplication we may not
be able to divide so while the ring is a
nice aelan group under addition things
may not be so nice with multiplication
but hey at least multiplication is
associative and to wrap things up
there's a rule which connects addition
and multiplication the distributive rule
all the numbers you studied in
arithmetic obey the distributive rule
the expressions in algebra do as well so
we're good
this isn't something new ladies and
gentlemen I give you the
rank